Hello!
My name is Olof Osterman.
I work on the National Bibliography at the Royal Library, and I am the one to do this instructional film over
How to catalog a translated book.
How to primarily catalogs a translated book I should say.
Some of these fields in this presentation are dealt with a little more clearly because they comply with the fields that
has been explained in an instructional film called Cataloging of Monography.
So many of the fields come back in this moment, or this movie so I just take them a little more clear.
And the book that we should start from is a book called Endurance by Alex Hutchinson.
When you catalog a book, of course, it is important that you are really sure that the book is not cataloged before
Because then you should use that item instead.
And it is below identifier.
And ISBN is the most common identifier for printed books.
That's how.
And the next field is distinctive addition and it is not a nuclear element so it
You do not need to fill in if you do not want to.
But if one thinks that
You need it so you can fill it in and we at NB fill in this field.
We can fill in that this book is hardcover
That's how.
If it had been stapled, we would have written a booklet instead.
And then there will be three fields that are just standard fields that we don't care about.
They are always in bibliographic items for printed books.
Then we have the title and there we will fill in the title itself and then we look at what it looks like on the title page.
The title page is the primary source so it is the one you should always start from.
So I fill in what is here.
And then there is endurance.
It is the title of this book.
And then we have another field, other title information, and here you can fill in the subtitle which is also in this book.
And then we have the subtitle the stretchable boundaries for your physical ability.
And you follow the title page as it looks.
You also describe the title page.
It is important.
And the next field is the copy of the.
And then we have the author written on the title page and we enter Alex Hutchinson, like that.
Since this is a translated book, we also want to include the translator's name.
So we specify the task as it is on the back of the title page.
And we also do this in this field of origin.
But since these two people have two different functions, the first, Alex Hutchinson, is a writer and the second
If translators are then we want to be special these two with an ISBD intersection.
If this other origin task had been in another field, we would not have had to do so.
Then it could have been created automatically.
But now we have to do it because they are the same field.
So we put in an ISBD internal point that is semicolon here.
And so we enter as it says on the back of the title page,
Translation: Lars Ahlström.
So, and then there were no other tasks that we wanted more from there.
So it's these two that are enough for it.
Then the origin is completed there and then the next task will be a paving task and then we have to look here in the book again.
And then we look for here in the book.
There is nothing on the title page.
And on the back of the title page we also have no publishing site.
Stockholm is mentioned in a copyright task but it is another type of task so we cannot take the task from there.
However, we can see that Nature & Culture, which is about here, belongs in Stockholm.
So then we know that we will enter Stockholm here in the place of publication.
But since there is no actual publishing site, we must cling Stockholm.
This is a nuclear element so you have to have a place of publication.
We add the publisher's name in agent - term.
And since the title page is the primary source, we start from it.
There it says Nature & Culture and we write as it says.
So, then we got that task.
And then the next task is year and date.
And in the first field you specify the year in numeric form.
And we probably have no real publishing year here.
But I can see that it is printed in 2019 and it is copyright 2019 also so then we know it is released in 2019.
So we put in that one
And then there was no real publishing year so we have to base our publishing year on the print year instead, 2019.
But we have to cling to this one then.
That's how
And since we base the release year on the print year, we also want to include it in the post.
Then we only write in 2019 here during manufacture.
The copyright year that comes next we will skip.
Scope, where you specify how many pages there are in the book.
It was 275 pages.
And then we have measured.
It is not a nuclear element so it is not something you have to add, but we at NB usually add it.
24 cm was the book, and what applies is that you always round up.
Other physical details.
The book contains no illustrations so you don't have to fill in anything here.
If you always put in the main title itself and skip the subtitles.
So we are content with Endure.
But if it is so uncertain about the preferred title, or the title of the original, then you can look at the different national bibliographies
What this title looks like in the original if you suspect it was something strange about it.
And this is a book that has been published in the UK from the beginning so maybe you should look at British Library first,
And see if it is there.
Otherwise, there are other catalogs too, e.g.
Classify.
But we are content with just endure here.
And then we will add another field that has to do with this being a translation.
And the next field is language.
Here is a language already.
But since it is the Swedish translation we catalog
Should this post have language: Swedish.
But we want to tell you that it is translated from English and that is what we should do now.